A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Self-Study Reports from Colleges and Universities FA799
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Self-Study Reports from Colleges and Universities
1966-1972
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA799
1.68 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes and 1 wide letter box
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of institutional self-study reports, primarily from historically Black colleges and universities. It is unclear from which Ford Foundation program(s) these reports originated.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series: Series 1. Institutional Self-Studies
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
In the 1960s and 1970s, the Ford Foundation was involved in strengthening the finances and curricula of Black colleges and universities through various programs. In 1973, the Foundation committed $50 million to a program that provided grants to eight private, historically Black colleges and universities. In 1968, the Ford Foundation provided grants totaling $3.5 million for curriculum development and improvement of business practices at predominately Black colleges and universities. Between 1972 and 1978, the Foundation committed another $50 million to provide scholarships to select minority students and faculty to continue their education. Between 1959 and 1965, the Ford Foundation allocated $32.8 million in grants to fifty-one college universities, and departments of education to help improve teacher education and attract better students to teaching careers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as part of Accession 2019:063 (Box 33656).
Education, Higher; Ford Foundation
- Institutional Self-Studies, 1966-1972; 1; 1.68 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes and 1 wide letter box
  - University of Michigan, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jarvis Christian College, 1971 April (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wiley College, 1970 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Grambling College of Louisiana, 1970 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Southern University and A&M College, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Texas Southern University, 1969 May (Box 2, Folder 6, Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bishop College, 1971 March (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Morristown College, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jackson State College, 1971 May (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tuskegee Institute, 1968 April (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Paine College, 1971 April (Box 4, Folder 12)